<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!--  Skill Actions  -->
    <string name="title_acrobatics">Acrobatics (DEX)</string>
    <string name="text_acrobatics">Acrobatics measures your ability to perform physical feats that require balance, coordination, and grace.</string>

    <string name="title_balance">Balance - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_balance">You can move across a narrow surface or uneven ground by attempting an Acrobatics check against the DC of the narrow surface or uneven ground. You start this action while in a square that contains a narrow surface, uneven ground, or another similar feature. You are always flat-footed while on a narrow surface or uneven ground.</string>
    <string name="success_balance">You move up to your Speed across the narrow surface or uneven ground, treating it as difficult terrain (see page 312).</string>
    <string name="critical_success_balance">You move up to your Speed across the narrow surface or uneven ground, treating it as normal terrain.</string>
    <string name="failure_balance">You must stay stationary (wasting the action) or you fall. If you fall, your turn ends.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_balance">You fall, and your turn ends.</string>

    <string name="title_escape">Escape - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_escape">When trying to escape from restraints or a creature’s Grapple, attempt an Acrobatics check. If you’re tied up by a creature, the escape DC is that creature’s Thievery DC. If you’re restrained by manacles or some other device, the DC is based on the type of restraint. Against a Grapple, the escape DC is the Grappling creature’s Athletics DC.</string>
    <string name="success_escape">You escape from the restraints or the Grapple, losing the grabbed or restrained condition.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_escape">Per a success, and you can move up to 5 feet. If you move, this action gains the move trait.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_escape">You don’t escape, and you take a –2 circumstance penalty to Acrobatics checks to Escape until the end of your current turn.</string>

    <string name="title_grab_edge">Grab Edge - reaction</string>
    <string name="text_grab_edge">When you fall off an edge or past an edge or some other form of handhold, you can use this reaction in an attempt to grab it, potentially stopping your fall. If you grab on, you can then Climb up using Athletics.</string>
    <string name="trigger_grab_edge">You fall from or past an edge or handhold.</string>
    <string name="requirement_grab_edge">Your hands are not tied behind your back or otherwise restrained.</string>
    <string name="success_grab_edge">If you have at least one hand free, you grab on to the edge or the handhold, stopping your fall. You still take damage from the distance fallen so far, but you treat the fall as though you had fallen 20 feet fewer. If you have no hands free, you continue to fall as if you had failed the check.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_grab_edge">You grab on to the edge or the handhold, whether or not you have a hand free, typically by using a suitable held item to catch yourself (catching a battle axe on a ledge, for example). You still take damage from the distance fallen so far, but you treat the fall as though you had fallen 30 feet fewer.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_grab_edge">You continue to fall, and if you’ve fallen 20 feet or more before you use this reaction, you take 10 bludgeoning damage from the impact for every 20 feet fallen.</string>
    <!--  Notes Falling  -->

    <string name="title_maintain_balance">Maintain Balance - free action</string>
    <string name="text_maintain_balance">You try to keep your balance to avoid falling.</string>
    <string name="trigger_maintain_balance">You take damage while standing on a narrow surface or uneven ground or otherwise have your balanced tested, as determined by the GM. You try to keep your balance to avoid falling.</string>
    <string name="success_maintain_balance">You keep your balance.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_maintain_balance">You keep your balance and don’t need to attempt further checks to Maintain Balance this round.</string>
    <string name="failure_maintain_balance">You fall.</string>
    <!--  Notes Falling, narrow surface, uneven ground  -->

    <string name="title_squeeze">Squeeze</string>
    <string name="text_squeeze">You attempt to squeeze through a small space by contorting your body to fit through.</string>
    <string name="success_squeeze">You squeeze through the tight space in 1 minute per 5 feet of squeezing.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_squeeze">You squeeze through the tight space in 1 minute per 10 feet of squeezing.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_squeeze">You become stuck in the tight space. While you’re stuck, you can spend 1 minute attempting another Acrobatics check at the same DC. Any result other than a critical failure causes you to become unstuck.</string>

    <string name="title_tumble_through">Tumble Through - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_tumble_through">You Stride up to your Speed. During this movement, you can try to move through the space of one enemy. Attempt an Acrobatics check against the enemy’s Reflex DC as soon as you try to enter its space. You can Tumble Through using Climb, Fly, Swim, or another movement type in the appropriate environment.</string>
    <string name="success_tumble_through">You move through the enemy’s space, treating the squares in its space as difficult terrain. If you don’t have enough Speed to move all the way through its space, you get the same effect as on a failure.</string>
    <string name="failure_tumble_through">Your movement ends, and you trigger reactions (such as Attacks of Opportunity) as if you had moved out of the square you started in.</string>

    <string name="title_maneuver_in_flight">Maneuver in Flight - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_maneuver_in_flight">If you have a fly Speed (see page 310) and you must conduct a difficult maneuver while flying, attempt an Acrobatics check.</string>
    <string name="success_maneuver_in_flight">You succeed at the maneuver.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_maneuver_in_flight">You succeed at the maneuver and gain a +2 circumstance bonus to your checks to Maneuver in Flight until the end of your next turn.</string>
    <string name="failure_maneuver_in_flight">Your maneuver fails, and the GM chooses whether you simply can’t move or some other detrimental effect happens. This consequence should be appropriate for the maneuver you attempted (for instance, being blown off course if you were trying to fly against a strong wind).</string>
    <!--  Notes Falling   -->

    <string name="title_arcana">Arcana (INT)</string>
    <string name="text_arcana">This skill measures how much you know about, arcane spells, and the most common magic items. Further, it determines how much information you have on theories about arcane energies as well as lore about the creatures associated with them. If you’re trained in Arcana, regardless of whether or not you’re a spellcaster, you’re versed in how to identify magic items, even those you normally would not be able to use.</string>

    <string name="title_recall_knowledge_arcana">Recall Knowledge - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_recall_knowledge_arcana">You attempt an Arcana check to try to remember a bit of knowledge regarding arcane theories, magic traditions, or creatures of arcane significance. The GM determines the DCs for such checks.</string>
    <string name="success_recall_knowledge_arcana">You recall the knowledge accurately.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_recall_knowledge_arcana">You recall incorrect information.</string>

    <string name="title_borrow_arcane_spell">Borrow an Arcane Spell</string>
    <string name="text_borrow_arcane_spell">If you’re an arcane spellcaster who prepares spells, during your daily preparations, you can attempt to prepare a spell from someone else’s spellbook. The GM sets the DC for the check (see Table 4–2 on page 146).</string>
    <string name="success_borrow_arcane_spell">You prepare the borrowed spell as part of your normal spell preparation.</string>
    <string name="failure_borrow_arcane_spell">You fail to prepare the spell, but the spell slot remains available for you to prepare a different spell. You can’t try to prepare this spell until the next time you prepare spells.</string>
    <!--   Notes daily preparation, table 4-2   -->
    
    <string name="title_identify_magic_arcana">Identify Magic</string>
    <string name="text_identify_magic_arcana">Once you discover that an item, location, or ongoing effect is magical, you can spend 10 minutes to attempt to identify the particulars of its magic. If your attempt is interrupted, you must start over. The GM sets the DC for your check (see Table 4–2 on page 146). Cursed or esoteric subjects usually have higher DCs or might even be impossible to identify using Arcana alone. Heightening a spell doesn’t increase the DC.</string>
    <string name="success_identify_magic_arcana">For an item or location, you get a sense of what it does and learn any means of activating it. For an ongoing effect, you learn the effect’s name and what it does. You can’t try again in hopes of getting a critical success.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_identify_magic_arcana">You learn all the attributes of the magic, including whether it is cursed.</string>
    <string name="failure_identify_magic_arcana">You fail to identify the magic and can’t try again for 1 day.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_identify_magic_arcana">You misidentify the magic as something else of the GM’s choice.</string>
    <!--    Notes table 4-2   -->

    <string name="title_learn_arcane_spell">Learn an Arcane Spell</string>
    <string name="text_learn_arcane_spell">If you are an arcane spellcaster, you can gain access to a new arcane spell from someone who knows that spell or from magical writing like a spellbook or scroll. To learn the spell, you must do the following.\n Spend 1 hour per level of the spell, during which you must remain in conversation with the person who knows the spell or have the magical writing in your possession.\n Have an amount of magical materials with a value indicated in Table 4–2 above.\n Attempt an Arcana check with a DC determined by the GM (see Table 4–2 above).</string>
    <string name="success_learn_arcane_spell">You expend the materials and learn the spell. If you have a spellbook, the spell is added to your spellbook; if you prepare spells from a list, it’s added to your list; if you have a spell repertoire, you can select it when you add or swap spells.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_learn_arcane_spell">Per a success, but you expend only half the cost in materials.</string>
    <string name="failure_learn_arcane_spell">You fail to learn the spell but can try again after you gain a level. The materials aren’t expended.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_learn_arcane_spell">Per a failure, plus you waste half the materials.</string>
    <!--   Notes table 4-2   -->
    
    <string name="title_read_magic">Read Magic</string>
    <string name="text_read_magic">You can read and understand magic writing as long as it is in a language you can normally read. This usually takes about 1 minute per page of text, but it could take longer in the case of ancient or obscure writings, or in other situations at the GM’s discretion. To read and understand the nuances of particularly archaic, esoteric, or obscure texts, the GM may require you to attempt an Arcana check to see if you understand the true meaning of the magic writing. The GM might have you attempt one check for the entire text or one check for each section of a larger text.</string>
    <string name="success_read_magic">You understand the true meaning of the text.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_read_magic">You misread the text.</string>
   
    <string name="title_athletics">Athletics (STR)</string>
    <string name="text_athletics">Training in Athletics is the result of conditioning that allows you to perform deeds of physical prowess.</string>
    
    <string name="title_break_grapple">Break Grapple - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_break_grapple">You attempt to break an opponent’s Grapple with an Athletics check against that creature’s Athletics DC.</string>
    <string name="success_break_grapple">You break free from your opponent’s Grapple and remove the grabbed or restrained conditions you gained from it.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_break_grapple">You remove the grabbed or restrained condition you gained from the opponent’s Grapple, and you can either knock the opponent prone or grab the opponent as if you succeeded at a Grapple against that creature. If you grab the opponent, this action gains the attack trait.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_break_grapple">If you were grabbed, you become restrained. If you’re already restrained, you can’t attempt to Break a Grapple again until the start of your next turn.</string>

    <string name="title_break_open">Break Open - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_break_open">Using your body, a lever, or some other tool, you attempt to forcefully open a door, window, or container; lift a heavygate; or break open some kind of bonds restraining your mobility. With a high enough result, you can even smash through walls.</string>
    <string name="success_break_open">You break the door, window, or container open, and the door, window, or container gains the broken condition.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_break_open">You open the door, window, or container but can avoid damaging it in the process.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_break_open">Your attempt jams the door, window, or container shut, imposing a –2 circumstance penalty on all future attempts to open it.</string>
    <!-- Notes broken  -->

    <string name="title_climb">Climb - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_climb">You move up, down, or across an incline. Unless the climb is particularly easy, you must attempt an Athletics check. The DC is determined by the GM based on the nature of the incline and any environmental circumstances. If you fall, the Grab Edge use of Acrobatics might allow you to catch yourself. You are flat-footed while climbing unless you have a climb Speed.</string>
    <string name="requirement_climb">You have both hands free.</string>
    <string name="success_climb">You move 5 feet up, across, or safely down the incline. If your Speed is 40 feet or greater, you move 10 feet instead.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_climb">You move half your Speed up, across, or safely down the incline.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_climb">You fall (see page 310). If you began the climb on stable ground, you fall and land prone.</string>

    <string name="title_grapple">Grapple - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_grapple">You attempt to grab an opponent. Grappling requires you to roll an Athletics check against the opponent’s Fortitude DC.</string>
    <string name="requirement_grapple">You have at least one free hand. Your target cannot be more than two sizes larger than you.</string>
    <string name="success_grapple">Your opponent is grabbed until the end of your next turn unless you move or your opponent Escapes using Acrobatics or Breaks the Grapple with Athletics.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_grapple">Your opponent is restrained until the end of your next turn unless you move or your opponent gets loose.</string>
    <string name="failure_grapple">You fail to grab your opponent. If you already had the opponent grabbed or restrained by way of a Grapple, those conditions on that creature end.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_grapple">If you already had the opponent grabbed or restrained, she gets free. Your target can grab you as if she succeeded at the Grapple action against you or force you to fall and land prone.</string>

    <string name="title_high_jump">High Jump - 2 actions</string>
    <string name="text_high_jump">You Stride, and if you move at least 10 feet, roll a DC 30 Athletics check in an attempt to Leap vertically. This DC might be increased or decreased due to the situation, as determined by the GM.</string>
    <string name="success_high_jump">You Leap, increasing the vertical distance to 5 feet.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_high_jump">You Leap, increasing your vertical distance to 8 feet or increasing your vertical distance to 5 feet and your horizontal distance to 10 feet.</string>
    <string name="failure_high_jump">You Leap the maximum height allowed by the Leap action.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_high_jump">Instead of Leaping, you fall prone in your space.</string>

    <string name="title_long_jump">Long Jump - 2 actions</string>
    <string name="text_long_jump">You Stride, and if you move at least 10 feet, roll an Athletics check in an attempt to Leap horizontally in the same direction. The DC of the check is equal to 5 plus the total distance in feet you’re attempting to move during your Leap (so Leaping 20 feet would require a DC 25 check). You can’t Leap farther than your Speed. This DC might be increased or decreased due to the situation, as determined by the GM.</string>
    <string name="success_long_jump">You Leap, increasing the distance you move horizontally to the desired distance.</string>
    <string name="failure_long_jump">You Leap the maximum distance allowed by the Leap action.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_long_jump">You Leap the maximum distance allowed by the Leap action, then fall prone.</string>

    <string name="title_shove">Shove - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_shove">You push an opponent away from you. Attempt an Athletics check against your opponent’s Fortitude DC.</string>
    <string name="requirement_shove">You have at least one hand free. The target can’t be more than two sizes larger than you.</string>
    <string name="success_shove">You push your opponent back 5 feet. You can move 5 feet in the same direction as your opponent. If you do, this action gains the move trait.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_shove">You push your opponent up to 10 feet back. You can move 10 feet in the same direction as your opponent. If you do, this action gains the move trait.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_shove">You lose your balance, fall, and land prone.</string>

    <string name="title_swim">Swim - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_swim">You use your arms and legs to swim through water. In most calm water, you succeed at the action without needing to attempt a check. If you must breathe air and you’re submerged in water, you must hold your breath each round. If you fail to hold your breath, you begin to drown (as described on page 315). If the water you are swimming in is turbulent or otherwise dangerous, you might have to attempt an Athletics check to Swim. If you end your turn in the water and haven’t succeeded at a Swim action that turn, you sink down 10 feet or float up 10 feet, as determined by the GM. However, if your last action on your turn was to enter the water, you don’t sink or float that turn.</string>
    <string name="success_swim">You move 5 feet horizontally through the water. If your Speed is 15 feet or greater, you move 10 feet instead, and if your Speed is 60 feet or greater, you move 15 feet instead. You can swim upward or downward, but doing so counts as moving through difficult terrain.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_swim">Per a success, but you can move an additional 5 feet.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_swim">You make no progress, and this action counts as 2 actions holding your breath.</string>

    <string name="title_trip">Trip - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_trip">You try to knock an opponent to the ground. Attempt an Athletics check against the target’s Reflex DC.</string>
    <string name="requirement_trip">You have at least one hand free. Your target can’t be more than two sizes larger than you.</string>
    <string name="success_trip">The target falls prone.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_trip">The target falls prone and takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_trip">You lose your balance and fall, and land prone.</string>

    <string name="title_disarm">Disarm - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_disarm">You try to knock something out of an opponent’s grasp. A Disarm attack requires you to roll an Athletics check against the opponent’s Reflex DC.</string>
    <string name="requirement_disarm">You have at least one hand free. The target can’t be more than two sizes larger than you.</string>
    <string name="success_disarm">You weaken your opponent’s grasp on the item. Until the start of that creature’s turn, attempts to Disarm the opponent of that item get a +2 circumstance bonus.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_disarm">You knock the item out of the opponent’s grasp. It falls to the ground in the opponent’s space.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_disarm">You lose your balance and become flat-footed until the start of your next turn.</string>

    <string name="title_crafting">Crafting (INT)</string>
    <string name="text_crafting">You can use this skill to create and repair items. This skill measures how much information you have on theories about alchemy as well as lore about the creatures associated with them. If you’re trained in Crafting, regardless of whether or not you’re an alchemist you’re versed in how to identify alchemical items, even those you normally would not be able to use.</string>

    <string name="title_recall_knowledge_crafting">Recall Knowledge - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_recall_knowledge_crafting">You attempt a Crafting check to try to remember a bit of knowledge regarding alchemical reactions, engineering equations, unusual materials, or creatures of alchemical or mechanical significance. The GM determines the DCs for such checks.</string>
    <string name="success_recall_knowledge_crafting">You recall the knowledge accurately.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_recall_knowledge_crafting">You recall incorrect information.</string>

    <string name="title_repair">Repair - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_repair">You spend an hour attempting to fix a dented or broken item. The GM sets the DC, but typically it’s more difficult to Repair a high quality or magic item. You can’t Repair a destroyed item.</string>
    <string name="requirement_repair">You must use a repair kit (see page 187).</string>
    <string name="success_repair">You remove 1 Dent from the item. In most cases, a dented item becomes fully restored and a broken item becomes only dented.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_repair">You fully restore the item.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_repair">You dent the item. If the item is magical, this Dent can’t destroy it.</string>

    <string name="title_craft">Craft - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_craft">You can make an item from raw materials. The GM determines the DC to Craft an item, which is based on its level, quality, and rarity, and might be affected by other circumstances. You need the Alchemical Crafting skill feat (page 162) to create alchemical items, the Magical Crafting skill feat (page 168) to create magic items, and the Snare Crafting feat (page 171) to create snares.\n To Craft an item, you must meet the following requirements:\n The item is your level or lower. (An item that doesn’t list a level is level 0.)\n You have the proficiency rank appropriate to the item’s quality. (See page 190.)\n You have the formula for the item.\n You have an appropriate set of tools and, in many cases, a workshop. For example, you need access to a smithy to forge a metal shield.\n You must supply raw materials worth at least half the item’s Price. You always expend at least that amount of raw materials when you Craft successfully. If you’re in a settlement, you can usually spend currency to get an equal amount of raw materials you need, except in the case of rarer special materials. \n You need to spend a minimum number of downtime days to Craft your item to a basic state of completion. This number depends on your level and the level of the item. You need to spend 4 downtime days for an item of your level. Reduce the number of days by 1 for each level by which your level exceeds the item’s level, to a minimum of 1 day. After spending this base number of days, you can either expend more materials to complete the item immediately or spend more days Crafting, completing the item more slowly but at lower cost. The success entry explains this mechanic further. You can Craft items with the consumable trait in batches, making up to four of the same item simultaneously. This requires you to include the raw materials for all the items in the batch at the start, and you must complete the batch all at once. After you expend the required amount of raw materials and base downtime, attempt a Crafting check. If you fail or critically fail, you can try to Craft the item again, but you have to start over.</string>
    <string name="success_craft">Your attempt to create the item is successful. You can pay the remaining half of the item’s Price to complete it immediately, or spend additional downtime days working on it. For each additional day you spend, reduce the value of the materials you need to expend to complete the item by an amount based on your level and proficiency rank (see Table 4–3). After any of these downtime days, you can complete the item by spending the remaining amount. If your downtime days are interrupted, you can return to finish the item later, continuing right where you left off.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_craft">Per a success, but each day you spend working reduces the remaining raw materials cost as though your level were 1 higher.</string>
    <string name="failure_craft">You fail to complete the item. You can salvage the raw materials you supplied for their full value.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_craft">You fail to complete the item. You ruin 10% of the raw materials you supplied, but can salvage the rest.</string>

    <string name="title_identify_alchemy">Identify Alchemy</string>
    <string name="text_identify_alchemy">You can identify the nature of an alchemical item with 10 minutes of testing using alchemist’s tools (see page 184 in Chapter 6: Equipment). The DC of the check is 10 plus the level of the item. If your attempt is interrupted in any way, you must start over.</string>
    <string name="requirement_identify_alchemy">You must use alchemist’s tools (see page 184).</string>
    <string name="success_identify_alchemy">You identify the item and the means of activating it.</string>
    <string name="failure_identify_alchemy">You fail to identify the item but can try again.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_identify_alchemy">You misidentify the item as another item of the GM’s choice.</string>

    <string name="title_deception">Deception (CHA)</string>
    <string name="text_deception">You can trick and bamboozle others through disguises, lies, and other forms of subterfuge.</string>

    <string name="title_create_diversion">Create a Diversion - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_create_diversion">With a gesture, a trick, or some distracting words, you can create a diversion that draws creatures’ attention elsewhere. If you use a gesture or trick, this action gains the manipulate trait. If you use distracting words, it gains the auditory and lingual traits. Attempt a single Deception check and compare it to the Perception DCs of the creatures whose attention you’re attempting to divert. Whether you succeed or fail, creatures you attempt to affect gain a +4 circumstance bonus to their Perception DCs against your attempts to Create a Diversion for 1 minute.</string>
    <string name="success_create_diversion">You become merely sensed, rather than seen, with regard to each creature whose Perception DC your result meets or exceeds. This lasts until the end of your turn or until you act to do anything except Step or use the Hide or Sneak actions of the Stealth skill (see page 158). If you do anything else, your sensed condition ends just before you act. For instance, if you succeed at a Deception check, momentarily becoming sensed by a creature (rather than seen), and then attack that creature, it is not flat-footed against your attack.</string>
    <string name="failure_create_diversion">You don’t divert the attention of any creatures whose Perception DC exceeds your result, and those creatures are aware you were trying to trick them.</string>


    <string name="title_impersonate">Impersonate</string>
    <string name="text_impersonate">You create a disguise to pass yourself off as someone or something you are not. Putting together a decent disguise takes 10 minutes and requires a disguise kit (see page 184), but a simpler, quicker disguise might do the job if you’re not trying to imitate a specific individual, at the GM’s discretion. In most cases, creatures have a chance to detect you only if they use the Seek action to roll Perception checks against your Deception DC. If you attempt to directly interact with someone while disguised, you need to roll a secret Deception check against that creature’s Perception DC instead. If you’re disguised as a specific individual, the GM might give creatures you interact with a bonus based on how well they know the person you’re imitating, or ask you to roll a secret Deception check even if you aren’t directly interacting with them.</string>
    <string name="success_impersonate">You trick the creature into thinking you’re the person you’re disguised as. You might have to attempt a new check if your behavior changes.</string>
    <string name="failure_impersonate">The creature can tell you’re not who you claim to be.</string>

    <string name="title_lie">Lie</string>
    <string name="text_lie">You try to fool someone with an untruth. Doing so takes at least 1 round, or longer if the lie is elaborate. You roll a single Deception check and compare it against the Perception DC of every creature you are trying to fool. The GM may modify this DC based on the situation and the nature of the lie you are trying to tell. Elaborate or highly unbelievable lies are much harder to get a creature to believe than simpler and more believable lies, and some lies are so big it’s impossible to get anyone to believe them. At the GM’s discretion, if a creature initially believes your lie, it might still be able to attempt a Perception check against your Deception DC (success on the creature’s part gains the failure effect below) to realize it’s a lie. This usually happens if the creature discovers enough evidence to counter your statements.</string>
    <string name="success_lie">The target believes your lie.</string>
    <string name="failure_lie">The target doesn’t believe your lie and gains a +4 circumstance bonus to Perception checks against further attempts by you to Lie to it for the duration of your conversation. The target is also more likely to be suspicious of you in the future.</string>


    <string name="title_feint">Feint - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_feint">With a misleading flourish, you leave an opponent unprepared for your real attack. You attempt a Deception check against that opponent’s Perception DC.</string>
    <string name="requirement_feint">You are within melee reach of the target</string>
    <string name="success_feint">The target is flat-footed against the next melee attack that you attempt against it before the end of your current turn.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_feint">The target is flat-footed against all melee attacks you attempt against it until the end of your next turn.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_feint">You are flat-footed against melee attacks the target attempts against you until the end of your next turn.</string>


    <string name="title_diplomacy">Diplomacy (CHA)</string>
    <string name="text_diplomacy">You influence others through negotiation and flattery.</string>

    <string name="title_gather_information">Gather Information</string>
    <string name="text_gather_information">You canvass local markets, taverns, and gathering places in an attempt to learn about a specific individual or topic. The GM determines the DC of the check and the amount of time it takes (typically if you spend an entire day of downtime to Gather Information, you can attempt three or four checks), along with any benefit you might be able to gain by spending coin on bribes, drinks, or gifts.</string>
    <string name="success_gather_information">You collect information about the individual or topic. The GM determines the specifics.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_gather_information">You collect incorrect information about the individual or topic.</string>

    <string name="title_make_impression">Make an Impression</string>
    <string name="text_make_impression">With at least 1 minute of conversation consisting of charismatic overtures, flattery, and other acts of goodwill, you seek to make a good impression on someone to make them temporarily agreeable. At the end of the conversation, attempt a Diplomacy check against the target’s Will DC, modified by any circumstances the GM sees fit. Good impressions (or bad impressions, on a critical failure) last for only the current social encounter unless the GM decides otherwise. The attempt fails if the target can’t understand you.</string>
    <string name="success_make_impression">The target’s attitude toward you improves by one step (from hostile to unfriendly, from unfriendly to indifferent, from indifferent to friendly, or from friendly to helpful).</string>
    <string name="critical_success_make_impression">The target’s attitude toward you improves by two steps (from hostile to indifferent, from unfriendly to friendly, or from indifferent or friendly to helpful).</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_make_impression">The target’s attitude toward you decreases by one step (from helpful to friendly, from friendly to indifferent, from indifferent to unfriendly, or from unfriendly to hostile.)</string>


    <string name="title_request">Request - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_request">You can make a request of a creature that’s friendly or helpful to you. You must couch the request in terms that the target would accept given their current attitude toward you. The GM sets the DC based on the difficulty of the request. Some requests are unsavory or impossible, and even a helpful NPC would never agree to them.</string>
    <string name="success_request">The target agrees to your request, but might demand added provisions or alterations to the request.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_request">The target agrees to your request without qualifications, or agrees to a request that would ordinarily require it to have an attitude one step better toward you.</string>
    <string name="failure_request">The target refuses the request, though she might propose an alternative that is less extreme.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_request">Not only does target refuse the request, but her attitude toward you also decreases by one step due to the temerity of the request.</string>

    <string name="title_intimidation">Intimidation (CHA)</string>
    <string name="text_intimidation">You bend others to your will through threats.</string>

    <string name="title_coerce">Coerce</string>
    <string name="text_coerce">With threats either veiled or overt, you attempt to intimidate a creature into doing what you want. You must spend at least 1 minute of conversation with a creature you can see and who can either see or sense you. At the end of the conversation, you attempt an Intimidation check against the target’s Will DC, modified by the circumstances at the GM’s discretion.</string>
    <string name="success_coerce">The target gives you the information you seek or agrees to follow your directives so long as they aren’t likely to harm the target in any way. The target continues to comply for an amount of time determined by the GM but not exceeding 1 day, at which point the target becomes unfriendly (if it wasn’t already unfriendly or hostile) and might act against you, including reporting you to the authorities.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_coerce">Per a success, but even afterward, the target is too scared of you to retaliate against you.</string>
    <string name="failure_coerce">The target doesn’t do what you say, and if it was not already unfriendly or hostile, it becomes unfriendly.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_coerce">The target doesn’t attempt the request, becomes hostile if it wasn’t already, and can’t be coerced by you for at least 1 week.</string>


    <string name="title_demoralize">Demoralize - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_demoralize">With a sudden shout, a well-timed taunt, or a cutting put-down, you can shake an enemy’s resolve. Choose a creature within 30 feet of you who you sense or see and who can sense or see you. Attempt an Intimidation check against that target’s Will DC. If the target does not understand the language you are speaking, you’re not speaking a language, or they can’t hear you, you take a –4 circumstance penalty to the check and demoralize loses the lingual trait.</string>
    <string name="success_demoralize">The target becomes frightened 1.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_demoralize">The target becomes frightened 2 and is fleeing until the end of its next turn.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_demoralize">You can’t attempt to demoralize the target again for 10 minutes.</string>

    <string name="title_lore">Lore (INT)</string>
    <string name="text_lore">You have specialized information on a narrow topic. Lore is different than other skills in two ways.\n First, the lore skill features many subcategories. You might have Military Lore, Sailing Lore, Vampire Lore, or any similar subcategory of skill. Each subcategory counts as its own skill, so applying a skill increase to Planar Lore wouldn’t increase your modifier with Sailing Lore. You gain a subcategory of the Lore skill from your background. The GM determines what other subcategories she’ll allow as Lore skills, though these categories are always less broad than any of the other skills that allow you to Recall Knowledge, and they should never be able to fully take the place of another skill’s ability to Recall Knowledge. For instance, you couldn’t choose Magic Lore in an attempt to recall the same breadth of knowledge covered by Arcana or Adventuring Lore in an attempt to gain all the information an adventurer would need.\n If you have multiple subcategories of Lore that could apply to a check, or that would overlap with another skill in the circumstances, you can choose to use the skill with the better skill modifier or that you would prefer to use. If there’s any doubt whether a Lore skill applies to a specific topic or use, the GM decides whether it can be used or not.</string>


    <string name="title_recall_knowledge_lore">Recall Knowledge - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_recall_knowledge_lore">You can use Lore to remember a bit of knowledge related to your type of Lore. The GM determines the DCs for such checks and whether your Lore applies to the topic.</string>
    <string name="success_recall_knowledge_lore">You recall the knowledge.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_recall_knowledge_lore">You recall erroneous knowledge.</string>


    <string name="title_practice_trade">Practice a Trade</string>
    <string name="text_practice_trade">You apply the practical benefits of your Lore specialty to earn money during periods of downtime. Practicing a Trade is most effective with Lore specialties such as business, law, or sailing, where there’s demand for workers. The GM might increase the DC if you’re attempting to use an obscure Lore skill to practice a trade.\n The GM assigns a task level representing the difficulty of the most lucrative job available. You can go looking for lower-level tasks, with the GM determining whether you find any. Sometimes you can attempt to find better work than the initial offerings, though this requires spending downtime to Gather Information or researching and socializing.\n When you take on a job, the GM sets the DC of your Lore check. The amount of money you can earn depends on the task level and your proficiency rank, as listed on Table 4–4: Skill Income. You might also need specialized tools to accept a job, like mining tools to work in a mine or a merchant’s scale to buy and sell valuables in a market. You need to spend a minimum number of downtime days to locate and secure the job, prepare to practice your trade, and get started on the task. This number depends on your level and the level of the task. You must spend 4 downtime days for a task of your level. Reduce the number of days by 1 for each level lower than you the task is, to a minimum of 1 day. Conversely, increase the number of days by 1 for each level higher than you the task is. After this base downtime, you earn your initial amount of money, and you can continue at the task to keep earning more.\n The success entry explains how this works. Note that if you want to earn money for working just 1 day, you need to pick a task that requires only 1 day of preparation. A 0-level task always requires 1 day. After you spend the base downtime to get started, roll your Lore check to determine your earnings. You continue to earn that amount each day for the duration of the job, without requiring further checks. The GM determines how long the job lasts, which is limited by how long the task will take to complete and other factors. Most tasks last a week or two, though some can take months or even years. If you stop in the middle of a task, normally you have to find a new task when you return, but the GM might decide that you can pick up where you left off (which usually happens only if the job is incomplete and the setup you did is still applicable).</string>
    <string name="success_practice_trade">You do competent work and gain the amount of currency listed on Table 4–4: Skill Income for the task level and your proficiency rank. You can spend further downtime days working at this job, earning the same amount each day, up to the task’s completion.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_practice_trade">You excel at the task. Per a success, but you earn money as though the task were 1 level higher. The GM might extend how long you can stay employed at the task.</string>
    <string name="failure_practice_trade">You do shoddy work and get paid the bare minimum for your time. You earn the amount listed in the failure column of Table 4–4: Skill Income. The GM will likely reduce how long you can continue at the task.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_practice_trade">You earn nothing for your work and are fired immediately. Your reputation suffers, potentially making it difficult for you to find rewarding jobs in that community in the future.</string>


    <string name="title_medicine">Medicine (WIS)</string>
    <string name="text_medicine">You can patch up wounds and help people recover from diseases and poisons.</string>

    <string name="title_administer_first_aid">Administer First Aid - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_administer_first_aid">You perform first aid on an adjacent creature that is at 0 Hit Points in an attempt to stabilize it. You can also perform first aid on an adjacent creature that is taking persistent bleed damage. The DC for either is 15. If a creature is both dying and bleeding, choose which effect you’re trying to treat each time you roll. You can administer First Aid again to attempt to remedy the other effect.</string>
    <string name="requirement_administer_first_aid">You must have healer’s tools (se page 186).</string>
    <string name="success_administer_first_aid">The creature at 0 Hit Points loses the dying condition (but remains unconscious), or you end the persistent bleed damage (see page 323).</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_administer_first_aid">The creature with 0 Hit Points has its dying condition increased by 1. A creature with persistent bleed damage takes damage equal to the amount of its persistent bleed damage.</string>


    <string name="title_analyze_forensics">Analyze Forensics</string>
    <string name="text_analyze_forensics">You spend 10 minutes checking for forensic evidence, such as bruising or wound patterns, to determine how a body was injured or killed.</string>
    <string name="success_analyze_forensics">You discover and correctly interpret a clue.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_analyze_forensics">You misinterpret a clue or incorrectly assume a false clue.</string>


    <string name="title_treat_disease">Treat Disease</string>
    <string name="text_treat_disease">You spend at least 8 hours caring for a diseased creature, helping it fight off a malady. Attempt a Medicine check against the disease’s DC.</string>
    <string name="requirement_treat_disease">You must have healer’s tools (see page 186).</string>
    <string name="success_treat_disease">You grant the creature a +2 circumstance bonus to its next saving throw against the disease.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_treat_disease">You grant the creature a +4 circumstance bonus to its next saving throw against the disease.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_treat_disease">Your efforts cause the creature to take a –2 circumstance penalty to its next save against the disease.</string>


    <string name="title_treat_poison">Treat Poison - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_treat_poison">You apply specialized treatments to prevent the spread of poison. Roll a Medicine check against the poison’s DC.</string>
    <string name="requirement_treat_poison">You must have healer’s tools (see page 186).</string>
    <string name="success_treat_poison">You grant the creature a +2 circumstance bonus to its next saving throw against the poison.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_treat_poison">You grant the creature a +4 circumstance bonus to its next saving throw against the poison.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_treat_poison">Your efforts cause the creature to take a –2 circumstance penalty to its next save against the poison.</string>


    <string name="title_treat_wounds">Treat Wounds - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_treat_wounds">You spend 10 minutes treating up to 6 injured living creatures (targeting yourself as one of them, if you so choose), then attempt a Medicine check. The DC is usually the medium DC for the highest level of patient you’re treating, though the GM might adjust this DC due to circumstances, such as trying to rest during volatile weather or when treating magically cursed wounds. A given creature can be subject to only one Treat Wounds attempt per 10-minute period, so two characters can’t treat the same target’s wounds simultaneously.</string>
    <string name="requirement_treat_wounds">You must use healer’s tools (see page 186).</string>
    <string name="success_treat_wounds">You treat the patients’ wounds. Each patient recovers Hit Points equal to its Constitution modifier × your level or equal to just your level, whichever is higher.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_treat_wounds">As success, but increase the healing by your level × 3.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_treat_wounds">The patients are bolstered against your Treat Wounds.</string>


    <string name="title_nature">Nature (WIS)</string>
    <string name="text_nature">You know a great deal about the natural world, and you can command and train animals and magical beasts.</string>

    <string name="title_command_animal">Command an Animal - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_command_animal">You issue an order to an animal that’s obeying you, either because you previously used Handle an Animal successfully (see below) or you have the Ride feat (see page 170). Most animals know the Leap, Seek, Stand, Stride, and Strike basic actions. If an animal knows an activity, such as a horse’s Gallop, you can command the animal to perform the activity, but you must spend as many Command an Animal actions as the activity’s number of actions. The animal uses the action you command.\n Most animals understand only the simplest instructions, so you might be able to instruct your animal to move to a certain square but not dictate a specific path to get there, or command it to attack a certain creature but not to make its attack nonlethal. The GM decides the specifics of the action your animal uses.</string>

    <string name="title_handle_animal">Handle an Animal - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_handle_animal">You prepare a helpful animal to accept your commands. If you are trained in Nature, you can use Handle an Animal on a friendly or indifferent animal as well.</string>
    <string name="success_handle_animal">Until the end of your turn, you can use the Command the Animal action to direct the animal. You can Mount the animal (see page 309).</string>


    <string name="title_recall_knowledge_nature">Recall Knowledge - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_recall_knowledge_nature">You can use Nature to remember a bit of knowledge on flora, fauna, geography, weather, the environment, or creatures of natural significance. The GM determines the DCs for such checks.</string>
    <string name="success_recall_knowledge_nature">You recall the knowledge accurately.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_recall_knowledge_nature">You recall incorrect information.</string>


    <string name="title_identify_magic_nature">Identify Magic</string>
    <string name="text_identify_magic_nature">Once you discover that an item, ongoing effect, or location is magical, you can spend 10 minutes to attempt to identify the nature and particulars of its magic. If your attempt is interrupted in any way, you must start over. The GM sets the DC for your check (see Table 4–2 on page 146). Cursed or particularly esoteric items usually have higher DCs or might even be impossible to identify using Nature alone. Heightening a spell doesn’t increase the DC.</string>
    <string name="success_identify_magic_nature">For an item or location, you get a sense of what it does and learn any means of activating it. For an ongoing effect, you learn the effect’s name and what it does. You can’t try again in hopes of getting a critical success.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_identify_magic_nature">You learn all the attributes of the magic, including whether it is cursed.</string>
    <string name="failure_identify_magic_nature">You fail to identify the magic and can’t try again for 1 day.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_identify_magic_nature">You misidentify the magic as something else of the GM’s choice.</string>

    <string name="title_learn_primal_spell">Learn a Primal Spell</string>
    <string name="text_learn_primal_spell">If you are a primal spellcaster, you can gain access to a new primal spell from someone who knows that spell or from magical writing like a spellbook or scroll. To learn the spell, you must do the following.\n Spend 1 hour per level of the spell, during which you must remain in conversation with the person who knows the spell or have the magical writing in your possession.\n Have an amount of magical materials with a value indicated in Table 4–2 on page 146.\n Attempt a Nature check with a DC determined by the GM (see Table 4–2).</string>
    <string name="success_learn_primal_spell">You expend the materials and learn the spell. If you have a spellbook, the spell is added to your spellbook; if you prepare spells from a list, it’s added to your list; if you have a spell repertoire, you can select it when you add or swap spells.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_learn_primal_spell">Per a success, but you expend only half the cost in materials.</string>
    <string name="failure_learn_primal_spell">You fail to learn the spell but can try again after you gain a level. The materials aren’t expended.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_learn_primal_spell">Per a failure, plus you waste half the materials</string>


    <string name="title_occultism">Occultism (INT)</string>
    <string name="text_occultism">You have a great deal of knowledge about ancient philosophies, esoteric lore, obscure mysticism, and supernatural creatures.</string>

    <string name="title_recall_knowledge_occultism">Recall Knowledge - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_recall_knowledge_occultism">You can use Occultism to remember a bit of knowledge regarding ancient mysteries, obscure philosophy, or creatures of occult significance. The GM determines the DCs for such checks.</string>
    <string name="success_recall_knowledge_occultism">You recall the knowledge accurately.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_recall_knowledge_occultism">You recall incorrect information.</string>


    <string name="title_identify_magic_occultism">Identify Magic</string>
    <string name="text_identify_magic_occultism">Once you discover that an item, ongoing effect, or location is magical, you can spend 10 minutes to attempt to identify the particulars of its magic. If your attempt is interrupted, you must start over. The GM sets the DC for your check (see Table 4–2 on page 146). Cursed or esoteric items usually have higher DCs or might even be impossible to identify using Occultism alone. Heightening a spell doesn’t increase the DC.</string>
    <string name="success_identify_magic_occultism">For an item or location, you get a sense of what it does and learn any means of activating it. For an ongoing effect, you learn the effect’s name and what it does. You can’t try again in hopes of getting a critical success.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_identify_magic_occultism">You learn all the attributes of the magic, including whether it is cursed.</string>
    <string name="failure_identify_magic_occultism">You fail to identify the magic and can’t try again for 1 day.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_identify_magic_occultism">You misidentify the magic as something else of the GM’s choice.</string>


    <string name="title_learn_occult_spell">Learn an Occult Spell</string>
    <string name="text_learn_occult_spell">If you are an occult spellcaster, you can gain access to a new occult spell from someone who knows that spell or from magical writing like a spellbook or scroll. To learn the spell, you must do the following. \n Spend 1 hour per level of the spell, during which you must remain in conversation with the person who knows the spell or have the magical writing in your possession.\n Have an amount of magical materials with a value indicated in Table 4–2 on page 146.\n Attempt an Occultism check with a DC determined by the GM (see Table 4–2).</string>
    <string name="success_learn_occult_spell">You expend the materials and learn the spell. If you have a spellbook, the spell is added to your spellbook; if you prepare spells from a list, it’s added to your list; if you have a spell repertoire, you can select it when you add or swap spells.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_learn_occult_spell">Per a success, but you expend only half the cost in materials.</string>
    <string name="failure_learn_occult_spell">You fail to learn the spell but can try again after you gain a level. The materials aren’t expended.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_learn_occult_spell">Per a failure, plus you waste half the materials.</string>


    <string name="title_read_esoterica">Read Esoterica</string>
    <string name="text_read_esoterica">You can read and understand occult writing, including complex metaphysical systems, syncretic principles, and incoherent ramblings, as long as it is in a language you can normally read. This usually takes about 1 minute per page of text. To read and understand the nuances of particularly archaic, esoteric, or obscure texts, the GM may require you to attempt an Occultism check to see if you understand the true meaning of the esoterica. The GM might have you attempt one check for the entire text or one check for each section of a larger text.</string>
    <string name="success_read_esoterica">You understand the true meaning of the text.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_read_esoterica">You misread the text.</string>


    <string name="title_performance">Performance (CHA)</string>
    <string name="text_performance">With this skill you can perform in front of crowds.\n Some performances require you to be more than just charismatic, and if you don’t meet the demands of the art form or the audience, the GM might apply a penalty based on the relevant ability score. For example, if you’re dancing and have a –1 Dexterity modifier, that penalty might apply to your dancing attempt. Likewise, if you are orating and have a –1 Intelligence modifier, you might have to hope your raw Charisma can overcome your intellectual shortcomings—or ask someone to help write your speeches!\n When you use an action or activity that utilizes the Performance skill, it gains one or more traits relevant to the type of performance. The GM might change these depending on the circumstances, but the most common performance-based traits are given below.\n Act or perform comedy: Usually auditory, lingual, and visual\n Dance: Move and visual\n Play an instrument: Auditory and manipulate\n Orate or sing: Auditory and lingual</string>

    <string name="title_perform">Perform - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_perform">When making a brief performance—one song, a quick dance, or a few jokes—you use the Perform action. This action is most useful when you want to prove your capability or impress someone quickly. Performing rarely has an impact on its own (unless you’re in a contest), but doing so might influence the DCs of subsequent Diplomacy checks against the observers if the GM sees fit.</string>
    <string name="success_perform">You prove yourself, and observers appreciate the quality of your performance.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_perform">Your performance impresses the observers, and they’re likely to share stories of your ability.</string>
    <string name="failure_perform">Your performance falls flat.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_perform">You demonstrate only incompetence.</string>


    <string name="title_stage_performance">Stage a Performance</string>
    <string name="text_stage_performance">During downtime, you perform for an audience to make money. The GM determines the levels of the audiences available and gives you a brief description of the most discerning (high-level) audience you could perform for. You can go looking for lower-level audiences, with the GM determining whether you find any. Sometimes you can attempt to find better audiences, though this requires spending downtime to Gather Information or researching and socializing. A typical audience of commoners on the street is a 0-level audience, but a group of artisans with more refined tastes might be a 2nd- or 3rd-level audience, and merchants, nobility, and royalty are increasingly higher level. The level of your audience is the task level for your performance. \n When you choose your audience, the GM secretly sets the DC of your Performance check. The amount of money you can earn depends on the task level and your proficiency rank, as listed on Table 4–4: Skill Income (see page 153). \n You need to spend a minimum number of downtime days to prepare for your performance, get out word to increase demand, allow time for the audience to plan attending, and play your first show. The exact number of days depends on your level and the level of the task. You must spend 4 downtime days for a task of your level. Reduce the number of days by 1 for each level lower than you the task is, to a minimum of 1 day. Conversely, increase the number of days by 1 for each level higher than you the task is. After this base duration, you earn your initial amount of money, and you can continue performing over subsequent days to keep earning more. The success entry explains how this works. Note that if you want to earn money for performing for just 1 day, you need to pick an audience that requires you to spend only 1 day of preparation. Performing for a 0-level audience always requires 1 day. After you spend the base downtime to get started, roll your Performance check to determine your earnings. If you do well, the GM might determine you can extend your performance, working more shows to bring in more money; this does not require further checks. Eventually, however, your performance will end because you’ve exhausted your audiences. The GM might let you perform the same show for other audiences, reducing or eliminating the preparation time but lowering the task level. \n Most performances can be staged for a couple weeks, or longer if you perform rarely and do other things with the rest of your downtime. Sometimes, taking time off from performing a show can draw in new high-level audiences, though this usually means you have to spend some time preparing again since you’re rusty.</string>
    <string name="success_stage_performance">Your performance is competent and moving. You’re rewarded with applause and whistles, plus the amount of currency listed on Table 4–4: Skill Income for the task level and your Performance proficiency rank. You can spend further downtime days on this performance, earning the same amount each day, until you exhaust your audience’s interest.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_stage_performance">Your performance inspires belly laughs, tears, or a change of heart among your audience. Per a success, but you earn money as though the task were 1 level higher. The GM might extend how long audiences stay interested.</string>
    <string name="failure_stage_performance">The audience is ambivalent or unimpressed by your performance. They respond with yawns and blank stares, and a few coins of pity. You earn the amount listed in the failure column of Table 4–4: Skill Income. The GM will likely reduce how long you can keep audience interest.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_stage_performance">Your awful performance turns the audience against you. They boo, hiss, and throw fruit or worse as they hassle you to end your performance. You earn nothing and your reputation suffers, potentially making it difficult to find discerning and rewarding audiences.</string>


    <string name="title_religion">Religion (WIS)</string>
    <string name="text_religion">The secrets of deities, dogma, faith, and the realms of divine creatures both sublime and sinister are open to you. You also understand how magic works, though your training gives a religious slant to that knowledge.</string>

    <string name="title_recall_knowledge_religion">Recall Knowledge - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_recall_knowledge_religion">You can use Religion to remember a bit of information on the subject of divine agents, the finer points of theology, and obscure myths regarding a faith. You can also recall some bit of lore about creatures with divine significance. The GM determines the DCs for such checks.</string>
    <string name="success_recall_knowledge_religion">You recall the knowledge accurately.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_recall_knowledge_religion">You recall incorrect information.</string>


    <string name="title_identify_magic_religion">Identify Magic</string>
    <string name="text_identify_magic_religion">Once you discover that an item, ongoing effect, or location is magical, you can spend 10 minutes to attempt to identify the particulars of its magic. If your attempt is interrupted, you must start over. The GM sets the DC for your check (see Table 4–2 on page 146). Cursed or esoteric items usually have higher DCs or might even be impossible to identify using Religion alone. Heightening a spell doesn’t increase the DC.</string>
    <string name="success_identify_magic_religion">For an item or location, you get a sense of what it does and learn any means of activating it. For an ongoing effect, you learn the effect’s name and what it does. You can’t try again in hopes of getting a critical success.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_identify_magic_religion">You learn all the attributes of the magic, including whether it is cursed.</string>
    <string name="failure_identify_magic_religion">You fail to identify the magic and can’t try again for 1 day.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_identify_magic_religion">You misidentify the magic as something else of the GM’s choice.</string>


    <string name="title_learn_divine_spell">Learn a Divine Spell</string>
    <string name="text_learn_divine_spell">If you’re a divine spellcaster, you can gain access to a new divine spell from someone who knows that spell or from magical writing like ancient text written on a temple wall or a scroll. To learn the spell, you must do the following.\n Spend 1 hour per level of the spell, during which you must remain in conversation with the person who knows the spell or have the magical writing in your possession.\n Have an amount of magical materials with a value indicated in Table 4–2 on page 146.\n Attempt a Religion check with a DC determined by the GM (see Table 4–2 on page 146).</string>
    <string name="success_learn_divine_spell">You expend the materials and learn the spell. If you have a spellbook, the spell is added to your spellbook; if you prepare spells from a list, it’s added to your list; if you have a spell repertoire, you can select it when you add or swap spells.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_learn_divine_spell">Per a success, but you expend only half the cost in materials.</string>
    <string name="failure_learn_divine_spell">You fail to learn the spell but can try again after you gain a level. The materials aren’t expended.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_learn_divine_spell">Per a failure, plus you waste half the materials.</string>


    <string name="title_read_scripture">Read Scripture</string>
    <string name="text_read_scripture">You can read and understand religious writing, including allegories, homilies, and proverbs, as long as it is in a language you can normally read. This usually takes about 1 minute per page of text. To read and understand the nuances of particularly archaic or obscure texts, the GM may require you to attempt a Religion check to see if you understand the true meaning of the scripture. The GM might have you attempt one check for the entire text or one check for each section of a larger text.</string>
    <string name="success_read_scripture">You understand the true meaning of the text.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_read_scripture">You misread the text.</string>

    <string name="title_society">Society (INT)</string>
    <string name="text_society">You understand the people and systems that make civilization run, and you know the historical events that make societies what they are today. Further, you can use that knowledge to navigate the twisted workings of settlements, whether they’re physical, societal, or economic.</string>

    <string name="title_recall_knowledge_society">Recall Knowledge - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_recall_knowledge_society">You can use Society to remember a bit of knowledge regarding local history, important personalities, and legal institutions, or about creatures with complex societies. The GM determines the DCs for such checks.</string>
    <string name="success_recall_knowledge_society">You recall the knowledge accurately.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_recall_knowledge_society">You recall incorrect information.</string>


    <string name="title_subsist_streets">Subsist on the Streets</string>
    <string name="text_subsist_streets">You find shelter and beg or scrounge enough food for at least yourself and maybe for other creatures as well. The GM determines the DC based on the nature of the settlement in which you are trying to subsist. You may need to have a minimum proficiency to use this downtime activity in more dangerous or highly organized settlements.</string>
    <string name="success_subsist_streets">You acquire enough food for yourself and your shelter gives you basic protection from the elements, providing a subsistence living.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_subsist_streets">You can either provide a subsistence living for yourself and one additional creature, or you can improve your own food and shelter, granting yourself a comfortable living.</string>
    <string name="failure_subsist_streets">You are exposed to the elements and don’t get enough food; you become fatigued until you attain sufficient food and shelter.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_subsist_streets">City guards, criminals, or other dangerous elements flush you out of your shelter and put you on notice, and you take a –2 circumstance penalty to Society checks to Subsist in the Streets for 1 week. You don’t find any food at all; if you don’t have any stored up, you’re in danger of starving or dying of thirst if you continue critically failing.</string>

    <string name="title_create_forgery">Create Forgery</string>
    <string name="text_create_forgery">You create a forged document, usually over the course of several hours, a day, or a week. You must have the proper writing material to create a forgery. If the document’s handwriting doesn’t need to be specific to a person, you need only to have seen a similar document before, and you gain up to a +4 circumstance bonus to the check (the GM determines the bonus). To forge a specific person’s handwriting, you need a sample of that person’s handwriting. Once someone observes the document, the GM rolls your Society check. If the result exceeds 20, the GM compares it to the observer’s Society DC. If the result is 20 or lower, the observer uses Perception or Society, whichever is higher. An observer who is closely scrutinizing documents on the lookout for a forgery can attempt a Perception or Society check against your Society DC (if they succeed, they know your document is a forgery). Once the GM rolls your check for a document, that same result is used no matter how many creatures observe that document.</string>
    <string name="success_create_forgery">The forgery goes undetected.</string>
    <string name="failure_create_forgery">The observer knows your document is a forgery.</string>

    <string name="title_decipher_writing">Decipher Writing</string>
    <string name="text_decipher_writing">You can take at least 1 minute per page (usually an hour per page or longer) in an attempt to decipher writing in an unfamiliar language, a coded message, or text written in an incomplete or archaic form. The DC is determined by the GM based on the state of the document.</string>
    <string name="success_decipher_writing">You understand the general content of the page.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_decipher_writing">You have a thorough understanding of the page’s content, if not an exact word-for-word translation.</string>
    <string name="failure_decipher_writing">You can’t understand the document and take a –5 circumstance penalty to further Society checks to decipher the writing on that page.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_decipher_writing">You believe you understand the text on that page, but you have in fact misconstrued its message.</string>

    <string name="title_stealth">Stealth (DEX)</string>
    <string name="text_stealth">You are skilled at avoiding detection, allowing you to slip past foes, hide, or conceal an item on your person.</string>

    <string name="title_conceal_object">Conceal an Object - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_conceal_object">Hiding a small object on your person (such as a weapon of light Bulk) requires a Stealth check. When you try to sneak a hidden object past someone who might notice it, the GM rolls your Stealth check and compares it to this passive observer’s Perception DC. If the creature is specifically searching you for an item, they can attempt a Perception check against your Stealth DC (finding the object on success). You can also conceal an object somewhere other than your person, such as among undergrowth or in a secret compartment within a piece of furniture. In this case, characters Seeking in an area compare their Perception check results to your Stealth DC to determine whether they find the object.</string>
    <string name="success_conceal_object">The object goes undetected.</string>
    <string name="failure_conceal_object">The searcher finds the object.</string>


    <string name="title_hide">Hide - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_hide">You huddle behind cover or deeper into concealment to become merely sensed, rather than seen (see page 302). The GM rolls your Stealth check in secret and compares the result to the Perception DC of each creature that could potentially see you but that you have cover against or are concealed from. If you successfully became sensed to a creature, but then cease to have cover against that creature or be concealed from it, it again sees you. Such creatures see you if you do anything other than Hide or Sneak, though the GM might allow you to perform a particularly unobtrusive action, activity, free action, or reaction without being noticed, possibly requiring another Stealth check.</string>
    <string name="success_hide">If the creature could see you, you’re now sensed by the creature instead of seen. If you were unseen by the creature, you remain unseen.</string>

    <string name="title_sneak">Sneak - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_sneak">You can attempt to move to another place while becoming or staying unseen. Stride up to half your Speed. (You can use Sneak while Burrowing, Climbing, Flying, or Swimming instead of Striding if you have the corresponding movement type.) The GM rolls your Stealth check in secret and compares the result to the Perception DCs of creatures that you were sensed or unseen by at the start of your movement. You automatically become seen if you don’t have cover or aren’t concealed from them at the end of the Sneak action, or as soon as you do anything other than Hide or Sneak. The GM might allow you to perform a particularly unobtrusive action, activity, free action, or reaction without being noticed, possibly requiring another Stealth check. If you speak or make a deliberate loud noise, you become sensed. If you succeed at your Stealth check and then attempt to Strike a creature, the creature remains flat-footed against that attack, and then you become seen. If you do anything else, you become seen just before you act. \n If you’re unseen by a creature and it’s impossible for that creature to see you (such as when you’re invisible, the observer is blinded, or you’re in darkness and the creature can’t see in darkness), you automatically treat the result of your d20 roll as a 20 against that creature on your checks to Sneak. You also continue to be unseen if you lose cover against or are no longer concealed from such a creature. Acting to do something other than Hide or Sneak makes you sensed instead of seen. If a creature senses you via Seek, you must Sneak to become unseen by it again.</string>
    <string name="success_sneak">You become unseen by the creature (or remain so) uring your movement and remain unseen by the creature at the end of it.</string>
    <string name="failure_sneak">You’re seen by the creature throughout your movement and remain so. If you’re invisible and were sensed by the creature, you’re still sensed throughout your movement and remain sensed, but you aren’t seen.</string>

    <string name="title_survival">Survival (WIS)</string>
    <string name="text_survival">You are skilled at living in the wilderness, foraging for food and building shelter, and with training you discover the secrets of tracking and hiding your trail.</string>

    <string name="title_sense_direction">Sense Direction</string>
    <string name="text_sense_direction">Using the stars, the position of the sun, traits of the geography or flora, or the behavior of fauna, you can stay oriented in the wild. Typically, you roll only once per day, but some environments or changes might necessitate rolling more often. The GM determines the DC and how long this activity takes. More exotic locales or those you’re unfamiliar with might require you to have a minimum proficiency rank to Sense Direction.</string>
    <string name="success_sense_direction">You gain enough orientation to avoid becoming hopelessly lost. If you are in an environment with cardinal directions, you have a sense of those directions.</string>


    <string name="title_survive_wild">Survive in the Wild</string>
    <string name="text_survive_wild">You build or maintain a shelter and forage enough food for yourself and maybe for other creatures as well. The GM determines the DC based on the nature of the wilderness you are trying to survive in. More exotic locales may require you to have a minimum proficiency rank to use this downtime-activity.</string>
    <string name="success_survive_wild">You forage enough food for yourself, and your shelter gives you basic protection from the elements, providing a subsistence living.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_survive_wild">You can either provide a subsistence living for yourself and one additional creature, or you can improve your own food and shelter, granting yourself a comfortable living.</string>
    <string name="failure_survive_wild">You are exposed to the elements and don’t get enough food, becoming fatigued until you get sufficient food and shelter.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_survive_wild">Your shelter is severely damaged or destroyed, and you take a –2 circumstance penalty to Survival checks to Survive in the Wild for 1 week. You don’t find any food at all; if you don’t have any stored up, you’re in danger of starving or dying of thirst if you continue critically failing.</string>


    <string name="title_cover_tracks">Cover Tracks - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_cover_tracks">You cover your tracks, moving at half your Speed. You don’t need to roll a Survival check to cover your tracks, but anyone tracking you must exceed your Survival DC if it is higher than the normal DC to track.</string>

    <string name="title_track">Track - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_track">You follow tracks, moving at half your Speed. After a successful check to Track, you can continue following the tracks at half your Speed without rolling additional checks for up to 1 hour. You need to attempt a check anytime something significant changes in the trail, as well as once every hour. The GM determines the DCs for such checks, depending on the freshness of the trail, the weather, and the type of ground.</string>
    <string name="success_track">You find the trail or continue to follow the one you’re already following.</string>
    <string name="failure_track">You lose the trail but can try again after a 1-hour delay.</string>

    <string name="title_thievery">Thievery (DEX)</string>
    <string name="text_thievery">You are trained in a particular set of skills favored by thieves and miscreants. Disabling devices and picking locks either are aided by or require the use of thieves’ tools (see page 187).</string>

    <string name="title_palm_object">Palm an Object - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_palm_object">Palming a small (usually of negligible Bulk), unattended object without being noticed requires a Thievery check against the Perception DCs of creatures who have you within their sight. You take the object whether or not you successfully conceal that you did so.</string>
    <string name="success_palm_object">If your result meets or exceeds every observer’s Perception DC, you palm the object without being detected.</string>
    <string name="failure_palm_object">If your result is lower than an observing creature’s Perception DC, that creature notices you palming the object. The GM determines the creature’s response.</string>


    <string name="title_steal_object">Steal an Object - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_steal_object">Stealing a small (usually of negligible Bulk) object from another person can be very difficult. If the object is worn but relatively unattended (like a loosely carried pouch filled with coins, or an object within such a pouch), the DC to steal the item without detection is equal to the creature’s Perception DC. You can’t steal an object that’s more closely guarded (in a pocket, for example), nor can you steal from a creature who is in combat or otherwise on guard. The GM determines the response of any creature that notices your theft. The GM might impose a penalty on your check if the nature of the object makes it harder to steal (such as a very small item in a large pack, or a sheet of parchment mixed in with other documents). The GM can also penalize the Perception DC of observers if they’re distracted.</string>
    <string name="success_steal_object">You steal the item without the bearer noticing, or an observer doesn’t see you take or attempt to take the item.</string>
    <string name="failure_steal_object">The item’s bearer notices your attempt before you can take the object, or an observer sees you take or attempt to take the item.</string>


    <string name="title_disable_device">Disable a Device - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_disable_device">This action allows you to disarm a trap or some other complex device. Often, a device requires numerous successes before becoming disabled, depending on its construction and complexity. Thieves’ tools are helpful and sometimes even required to disable a device, as determined by the GM, and sometimes a device requires a higher proficiency rank in Thievery to disable it.</string>
    <string name="requirement_disable_device">Some devices require you to use thieves’ tools (see page 187) when disabling them.</string>
    <string name="success_disable_device">You achieve one success toward disabling the device.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_disable_device">You achieve two successes toward disabling the device. If you complete the process of disabling the device with this check, you leave no trace of your tampering, and you can rearm the device later, if the type of device can be rearmed.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_disable_device">You either undo one success you’ve already gained or, if you have no successes, you set off the device.</string>


    <string name="title_pick_lock">Pick a Lock - 1 action</string>
    <string name="text_pick_lock">Opening a lock without a key is very similar to Disabling a Device, but the DC of the check is determined by the complexity and construction of the lock you are attempting to pick. Unlocking even the simplest of mechanisms almost always requires three or more successful checks to accomplish. If you lack the proper tools, the GM might let you used improvised picks, which are treated as poor-quality tools.</string>
    <string name="requirement_pick_lock">You must be using thieves’ tools (see page 187).</string>
    <string name="success_pick_lock">You gain one success toward opening the lock.</string>
    <string name="critical_success_pick_lock">You gain two successes toward opening the lock.</string>
    <string name="critical_failure_pick_lock">You either undo one success you have already gained, or, if you have no successes, you break your tools. The tools can be used while broken, but are treated as poor quality tools. Repairing them requires replacing the tools (costing 6 sp, or 50 sp for expert-quality thieves’ tools).</string>
</resources>